adjusting allocated costs before
posting in business Central when you
work with allocation accounts the split
happens when the expense is posted
according to the definition of your
allocation accounts but what if I wanted
to see or make some adjustments to the
amounts that have been split before
posting there's a great function for
that let's take a look at that in the
general
journals I search for General journals
and select the search result now let's
create our expense let's say this is an
invoice and I want to select my
allocation
account so here I have an allocation
account that's called split by three it
basically just splits the amount into
three different accounts with an equal
share let's say the amount is 10,000 now
I can choose actions functions generate
lines from a location account
line this will now split up just as
defined in my allocation account up into
these individual G accounts and now I
can make any adjustments I wish to make
before
posting so this function is a great way
to intercept or make adjustments before
posting with allocation
accounts thank you for watching